<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Evocations</title>
    <link>http://www.evocations.info/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Evocations</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>evocations.info 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.evocations.info/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Booting a Preexisting OS in Virtualbox</title>
      <link>http://www.evocations.info/blog/2020/01/booting-a-preexisting-os-in-virtualbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.evocations.info/blog/2020/01/booting-a-preexisting-os-in-virtualbox/</guid>
      <description>I had an idea to get around rebooting to play some of the Windows games I enjoy. Why not virtualize a windows environment? What kind of performance can I get from a Windows VM?
Unfortunately, not great performance without some serious tinkering.
My current configuration is dual-boot Windows (Gaming) and Arch Linux (Work/Browsing). Quite a lot of my data was created before installing Linux, and at this point, would be too much of a hastle to organize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch boot broken due to umount /boot</title>
      <link>http://www.evocations.info/blog/2020/01/arch-boot-broken-due-to-umount-boot-boot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.evocations.info/blog/2020/01/arch-boot-broken-due-to-umount-boot-boot/</guid>
      <description>I can’t pin down exactly when it happened, but at some point my laptop’s Arch partition stopped booting. It would give me an error “You must load the Linux kernel first!” What in hell do you mean by that? What changed since last week? You were fine last time I used you!
I suspected an issue with GRUB, but I understand now what actually happened. Some how, Linux had upgraded without /boot mounted, causing a version discrepency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Removing Python on Raspbian causes some unforseen problems</title>
      <link>http://www.evocations.info/blog/2020/01/removing-python-on-raspbian-causes-some-unforseen-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 15:12:44 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.evocations.info/blog/2020/01/removing-python-on-raspbian-causes-some-unforseen-problems/</guid>
      <description>On Raspbian, I was having an issue with Python3. My first instinct was to uninstall and reinstall.
Que “I can fix it”:
$ sudo apt remove python3  “Oh f#@&amp;amp;”
Turns out, Debian (And by extension Raspbian) uses Python for tons of things.
Que: Panic. A lot of it. I started mashing CTRL-C
In the end it didn’t uninstall too many things, and my terminal was still functioning, so I tried to repair the damage.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>